<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
        <title>Saevon</title>
        <description>Saevon - Saevon</description>
        <link>www.saevon.ca</link>
        <link>www.saevon.ca</link>
        <lastBuildDate>2013-10-04T18:04:20-04:00</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>2013-10-04T18:04:20-04:00</pubDate>
        <ttl>1800</ttl>


        <item>
                <title>Review: Game Dev Tycoon</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Game Dev Tycoon is an interesting game that puts the player into the shoes of a game developer from the 80&#39;s. Re-invent your favourite games, combat piracy, or even embrace it. Its a unique game due to its differing gameplay between the legit and pirated versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick warning, this review is written just before the move to the 3rd office, and thus might not fully reflect all the game options. I just felt it was best to write this while its fresh in my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.greenheartgames.com/2013/04/29/what-happens-when-pirates-play-a-game-development-simulator-and-then-go-bankrupt-because-of-piracy/&quot;&gt;See this link for details about the piracy aspect.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Controls&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game uses a menu for most of its controls, you click on the screen and a menu opens up. I found this a bit unweldy, as sometimes this meant it went above the other icons at the top, making them hard to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was also a minor bug that made me sometimes manipulate a menu in the background while I was on the &quot;New Game&quot; window. I&#39;d be trying to click to type the game name, but be clicking on menu options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One suggestion which I thought would be nice, would be to highlight staff when you hover over them, that would make it more obvious that there are seperate menus. Thought it was pretty clear after a click or two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Gameplay&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the game was a bit confusing, I was always just guessing what options to choose, and sometimes the game I imagined and the game that I apparantly made didn&#39;t match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game creation menu was nice, but sometimes I wish I could cross some genres such as Zombie/Horror.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three stages were also a little confusing, I had already made tons of games by this point, yet the requirements still eluded me. If I was actually making games, after that many games and game reports I would have long since compiled the effects of each stage on the topics and genres. While I sometime get hints saying &quot;+++?&quot; it just didn&#39;t seem like I was getting enough for my efforts, sure I could have actually written reports myself, but this is a casual game to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also found the &quot;Design&quot; and &quot;Technology&quot; bubbles to be confusing, I had no idea what it meant to get better points there, except that it was probably good. Nor how each staff member and choice could effect it. My characters had stats, but I couldn&#39;t figure out why I&#39;d care for that very reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research was pretty well done, I found that I could mostly guess when I&#39;d get lots of research points, it was intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When choosing projects to work on, I felt I should have more control over who does what, while I could train, and research individually, it would be nice to do that as a group as well. Conversely I felt that my staff could produce multiple games, as I could do them by myself at the start, especially when I really needed money, and didn&#39;t mind going red to get money faster&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a similar topic, the medium game didn&#39;t tell me my team would have been swamped and incapable of finishing it without giving 130% each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Graphics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the graphics to be to my liking, the cartoonish sprites, and backgrounds to be very fitting. They didn&#39;t take too much of the focus, making you see the whole office as important, rather than focusing on your individual avatar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the avatar, I found there wasn&#39;t too much options for making an avatar, I think hair style and colour could have been seperated. Otherwise I had all the options I needed to get someone I liked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The time bar at the top left was not very well done either, as I found the numbers just faded away and were unimportant to me. If it was more obvious what year it was (1980 + the given year I guess) it might have been nice, especially when I was talking to my friends about how I released these cool games in (what year would this be again?). I remember one conversation vividly, where my friend stated, &quot;maybe the world isn&#39;t ready for your ground breaking Zombie/Sim :P&quot;, and I took forever to figure out what year that was in real time. The other time values could have been better shown as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Sounds&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the sounds were okay, they were reminiscent of the much older games I liked to play, and totally fit in with the time and feel of the game. However there wasn&#39;t much more about them, thus I can see how the developers took their own gameplay to heart, not putting much effort into the sounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall I did like them, and feel that the game really didn&#39;t need much effort in this category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game was a very fun game, however I still felt there was room for improvement. I wish the best of luck to the developers of this game, and hope their sequel or expansion is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.greenheartgames.com/2013/04/29/what-happens-when-pirates-play-a-game-development-simulator-and-then-go-bankrupt-because-of-piracy/&quot;&gt;Piracy in a game dev game!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
                <link>www.saevon.ca/media/review-game-dev-tycoon</link>
                <guid>www.saevon.ca/media/review-game-dev-tycoon</guid>
                <pubDate>2013-10-04T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Installing Pygame on Mac 10.8 Mountain Lion</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;So I&#39;m currently trying to install pygame for my mac, and man do I have tons of compilation problems. I&#39;ll list the solutions I found for every problem I have along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the following guide to install pygame, the 10.7 one which was the closest I could find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pygame.org/wiki/MacCompile&quot;&gt;Installing Pygame&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Problems&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;src/scale_mmx64.c:499:27: error: invalid instruction mnemonic &#39;movsxl&#39;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pygame.org/wiki/MacCompile&quot;&gt;Installing Pygame&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
                <link>www.saevon.ca/coding/installing-pygame-on-mac-108-mountain-lion</link>
                <guid>www.saevon.ca/coding/installing-pygame-on-mac-108-mountain-lion</guid>
                <pubDate>2013-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Python Virtual Environments and PIP</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;virtualenv is a pretty awesome tool for any python user, however it is often too easy to accidentaly install new pacakges into the wrong place. Here I show you how to separate your system packages and that of your project environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jump straight to the &lt;a href=&quot;#Syspip&quot;&gt;Syspip&lt;/a&gt; section if you know all about python packaging and virtualenv.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;virtualenvwrapper&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a really useful tool, even if it adds binaries with amazingly long names. It lets you easily and quickly list, add, and switch to a virtualenv.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t usually need all the many options this script provides, and would also prefer for it to be easier to combine the virtualenvwrapper&#39;s and git&#39;s PS1 prompt changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Changing Environments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To change environments is pretty easy, you just use the &lt;code&gt;workon&lt;/code&gt; command. This works whether you have a currently active environment or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;workon &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$env_name&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;To deactivate the current environment you use the &lt;code&gt;deactivate&lt;/code&gt; command, just like normal. Though personally I though workoff was more obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;deactivate
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Tab Completion!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When using the &lt;code&gt;workon&lt;/code&gt; command you can tab complete to see the list of all the environments you have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Add/Remove Environments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Add a new environment&lt;/span&gt;
mkvirtualenv &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$env_name&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Remove an environment&lt;/span&gt;
rmvirtualenv &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$env_name&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h1&gt;Syspip&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heres where stuff gets interesting. To prevent mistakes while installing packages, I&#39;ve added the following things to my bash startup scripts (&lt;code&gt;.bashrc&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.bash_aliases&lt;/code&gt;, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# .bashrc&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;source&lt;/span&gt; /usr/local/bin/virtualenvwrapper.sh

&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;export &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;WORKON_HOME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$HOME&lt;/span&gt;/.environments
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;export &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;PIP_VIRTUALENV_BASE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;WORKON_HOME

&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;export &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;PIP_REQUIRE_VIRTUALENV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;First notice that we set &lt;code&gt;PIP_REQUIRE_VIRTUALENV&lt;/code&gt;, this ensures that pip &lt;em&gt;will not&lt;/em&gt; run without an active virtual environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, do remember to set &lt;code&gt;PIP_VIRTUALENV_BASE&lt;/code&gt;, since that is what pip uses to tell if you have an environment active. (AFAIK)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# .bash_aliases&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;export &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;SYSTEM_PIP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sb&quot;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;which pip&lt;span class=&quot;sb&quot;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;function &lt;/span&gt;syspip &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;PIP_REQUIRE_VIRTUALENV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; sudo &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$SYSTEM_PIP&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;$@&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Here we first find which version of pip we use, then add a new way of using the global pip binary. Now you have 2 ways of installing a package, each of which always installs to the expected location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;pip install $package&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To install &lt;strong&gt;only&lt;/strong&gt; for the currently active environment, (or fail if it doesn&#39;t find one)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;syspip install $package&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To install &lt;strong&gt;only&lt;/strong&gt; globally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;alert alert-block alert-warning&quot;&gt; &lt;i class=&quot;icon-warning-sign&quot;&gt; &lt;/i&gt; 
    Don&#39;t forget to load &lt;code&gt;.bash_aliases&lt;/code&gt; before you activate any environments, otherwise &lt;code&gt;syspip&lt;/code&gt; might not work as advertised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



</description>
                <link>www.saevon.ca/coding/python-virtual-environments-and-pip</link>
                <guid>www.saevon.ca/coding/python-virtual-environments-and-pip</guid>
                <pubDate>2013-07-12T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Review: Alex Rider</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Alex Rider is a story about a kid learning the truth about his parent. Having been secretly trained as a spy from birth, he&#39;s coerced into working for the MI6 and always ends up saving the world from unknown catastrophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been a while since I last read books from the Alex Rider series, but I can tell you they&#39;re worth re-reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general plot follows Alex as he gets into difficult situations and uses his wits, training, and cool gadgets to escape hazards. He often not only triumphs, but comes out ahead, finding some new source of information which helps him uncover the final evil plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The series is quite easy to be immersed in, and nicely portrays the problems and challenges a spy might be facing. Some potential inaccuracy does exist, however it is outshadowed by the greater benefit it usually presents to the overall story. You can see that the author did his research, and consulted experts in quite a few fields when writing his books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main characteristics of this series is that Alex does not often wish to follow along with every Secret Service&#39;s requests for help. This is very realistic portrayal of the most likely reaction of a kid put in the situation he faces, and while I would prefer not to see him being coerced into these situations, it makes Alex seem much more normal and provides more believability to the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The evil villains of the Alex Rider universe do follow the standard James Bond procedure, but all seem to have unique quirks that make them much more. Not all of them would blab out their evil plan when Alex is caught and about to be killed, though most of them do end up leaving him to die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Psychology plays a big part in the series, as we see Alex get hurt mentally with everything he goes through, and even though he seems to get back up a little too resiliently, it makes reading the books all the more accurate and enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>www.saevon.ca/media/review-alex-rider</link>
                <guid>www.saevon.ca/media/review-alex-rider</guid>
                <pubDate>2013-07-08T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>WebRTC with JsSIP and Asterisk</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I&#39;ve been trying to get a web phone up and running, my only real requirement was to use Asterisk. So I decided to go with the following technology stack, JsSIP, Chrome and Asterisk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Browsers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve only tried to use chrome so far, though I&#39;ve read that Firefox is currently WebRTC capable as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chrome on OSX seems to work fine (version 27.0.1453.116).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chrome on Ubuntu had problems until I updated to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntuupdates.org/package/google_chrome/stable/main/base/google-chrome-beta&quot;&gt;Beta version&lt;/a&gt; (version 28.0.1500.52 beta)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Asterisk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asterisk had quite a few requirements before I could get it to work with WebRTC, &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.asterisk.org/wiki/display/AST/Asterisk+WebRTC+Support&quot; title=&quot;Asterisk and WebRTC&quot;&gt;see this page for details&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Building&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will likely need to rebuild Asterisk as WebRTC requires a SRTP libraries, which aren&#39;t included by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will need the following libraries on the machine you use to recompile Asterisk:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;libssl-dev&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;libsrtp0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Once you have these libraries installed, you will also need to enable two Asterisk resources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;res_srtp.so&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;res_http_websocket.so&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now you can recompile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The resulting build might also need a few configuration changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/etc/asterisk/
  |-- http.conf
  |-- modules.conf
  |-- sip.conf
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;http.conf&lt;/code&gt;
  Ensure the following options are set&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  enabled=yes
  bindaddr=0.0.0.0
  bindport=8088
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;modules.conf&lt;/code&gt;
  you must load res_http_websocket.so before chan_sip.so&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sip.conf&lt;/code&gt;
  Any users that you want to allow WebRTC for you need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  encryption=yes
  avpf=yes
  transport=ws,wss
  icesupport=yes
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;  Adding &lt;strong&gt;encryption=yes&lt;/strong&gt; to any non WebRTC phones might make them break, so be careful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;alert alert-block alert-info&quot;&gt; &lt;i class=&quot;icon-info-sign&quot;&gt; &lt;/i&gt; 
    Remember to restart Asterisk once you&#39;re done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;JsSIP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JsSIP &lt;a href=&quot;http://jssip.net/&quot; title=&quot;JsSip&quot;&gt;JsSIP&lt;/a&gt; was quite easy to use, however it wasn&#39;t without its set of problems. If you want to do a quick test yourself, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jssip.tryit.net&quot; title=&quot;JsSip Tryit&quot;&gt;JsSIP Tryit&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main problem was that their script didn&#39;t seem to connect with asterisk properly, though I&#39;ve already forgotten the reason (will update if I do). To solve this I updated to the dev version of JsSIP, which I download from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jssip.tryit.net&quot; title=&quot;JsSip Tryit&quot;&gt;JsSIP Tryit&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards I would also have jssip error out when I tried to type in an invalid target, I patched it quickly removing the potentially erroneous code. I didn&#39;t know enough about their side of the problem, so I have no way of knowing if this is a correct fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;alert alert-block alert-warning&quot;&gt; &lt;i class=&quot;icon-warning-sign&quot;&gt; &lt;/i&gt; 
    I&#39;ve included the patch below, use it at your own risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;diff&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gh&quot;&gt;Index: /static/js/jssip-devel.js&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gh&quot;&gt;===================================================================&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gd&quot;&gt;--- /static/js/jssip-devel.js&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gi&quot;&gt;+++ /static/js/jssip-devel.js&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gu&quot;&gt;@@ -3372,5 +3372,10 @@&lt;/span&gt;
         console.log(LOG_PREFIX +&amp;#39;ICE candidate received: &amp;#39;+ e.candidate.candidate);
       } else {
&lt;span class=&quot;gd&quot;&gt;-        self.onIceCompleted();&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gi&quot;&gt;+       // PATCH: (saevon) Fixes bug with the code crashing at this step.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gi&quot;&gt;+       // since: neither createOffer nor createAnswer get called if you&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gi&quot;&gt;+       // had an &amp;quot;Invalid Target&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gi&quot;&gt;+       // Thus the method doesn&amp;#39;t get added yet&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gi&quot;&gt;+       if (self.onIceCompleted) {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gi&quot;&gt;+           self.onIceCompleted();&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gi&quot;&gt;+       }&lt;/span&gt;
       }
     };
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;One-Way Audio&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was one unexpected problem that seems to have been causing one way audio for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the &lt;strong&gt;call_start&lt;/strong&gt; event fires you have a few methods you can use to get the local and remote streams, which would be quite useful for video, except I wasn&#39;t using video at the time. So I ended up ignoring these callbacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unexpectedly the only way to get sound back was in fact through the remote stream, which I would then attach to a video tag on my html page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;call&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;on&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;started&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;call&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;getRemoteStreams&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;length&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;remoteView&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;document&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;getElementById&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;remoteView&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;remoteView&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;src&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;window&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;createObjectUrl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;call&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;getRemoteStreams&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WebRTC is clearly still a work in progress, and I hope it gets polished up nicely for when I next wish to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jssip.net/&quot; title=&quot;JsSip&quot;&gt;JsSIP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jssip.tryit.net&quot; title=&quot;JsSip Tryit&quot;&gt;JsSip Tryit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.asterisk.org/wiki/display/AST/Asterisk+WebRTC+Support&quot; title=&quot;Asterisk and WebRTC&quot;&gt;Asterisk and WebRTC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
                <link>www.saevon.ca/coding/webrtc-with-jssip-and-asterisk</link>
                <guid>www.saevon.ca/coding/webrtc-with-jssip-and-asterisk</guid>
                <pubDate>2013-07-04T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Hello World!</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my Blog!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&#39;ve finally decided to get myself a blog, after seeing a few options I decided to go with Jekyll and Github Pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel this blog could combine most of my passions, coding, movies, and anything else I feel like blogging about. To that end my goal is to separate the main page into multiple post groups. Each group would let you see new posts from that category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I add more topics I will update this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Coding&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would list any CS related topics, and though the title is &quot;Coding&quot; it would include algorithms and other such theoretical topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Media&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would be a conglomeration of any movies, books, and other such topics. Mostly this will compose of reviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Rant&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miscellaneous talks will go here&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;alert alert-block alert-success&quot;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Thank you&lt;/strong&gt; for reading this far&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Expect to see many changes for the next month (or a few more than that) as I customize this blog and personalize as much as I can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>www.saevon.ca/misc/hello-world</link>
                <guid>www.saevon.ca/misc/hello-world</guid>
                <pubDate>2013-07-03T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>


</channel>
</rss>
