<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Saevon.ca</title><link>//blog.saevon.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link href="/feeds/dd.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Kaern's Blade</title><link>//blog.saevon.ca/roleplaying/kaerns-blade/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magical Item:&lt;/strong&gt; A merciful sword that refuses to kill its foes, but eagerly drinks in magic. Its main purpose is to absorb all magic, refusing to be sheathed if its purpose isn't met.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="summary"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;+3 flutter blade (1Handed, 1d4+1d6 piercing or slashing, 19-20 Crit)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move action to switch between slashing and piercing damage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Symbols on it pulse with a faint sky blue light (rad 10' bright, rad 15' shadowy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Merciful&lt;/strong&gt;: Only does subdual damage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mage Killer&lt;/strong&gt;: On successful hit can steal magic (see below)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;+6 vs Magic items or effects (see below)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cursed Item&lt;/strong&gt;: You can't sheathe the blade without draining magic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="mage-killer"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Mage Killer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every successful hit with this blade steals magic, choose one of the following for the blade to eat:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Up 6 spell levels worth of spells/day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Up to 2 uses of a &lt;strong&gt;Su&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Sp&lt;/strong&gt; ability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One infinite use &lt;strong&gt;Su&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Sp&lt;/strong&gt; ability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any spell affect currently on the user&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any effects of a magical item, disabling it for 1 hour&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a magical item provides multiple bonuses, only one is disabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e.g. +2 Keen Flaming Weapon: Only one of those 3 effects can be stolen per attack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that any ability that is the equivalent of a &lt;strong&gt;7th&lt;/strong&gt; level spell or higher cannot be stolen. Also Kaern's Blade cannot affect artifacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a &lt;strong&gt;Confirmed Critical&lt;/strong&gt; instead of doing bonus damage, the user can steal the magic instead, being able to store it in the blade for up to &lt;strong&gt;1 Hour&lt;/strong&gt;. The user can then cast/use as if he is the original source of the magic. If the original source is destroyed, the magic is lost as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The owner can specifically choose to target an effect or magical item, treat this as a &lt;strong&gt;called shot&lt;/strong&gt;, but with a &lt;strong&gt;+6 Echantment&lt;/strong&gt; bonus. However when using this the weapon does no damage at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="alert alert-info "&gt;&lt;i class="fa fa-info-circle"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Optional&lt;/strong&gt;: You can even have the blade be able to absorb magic being cast on it. If the user readies a standard action to defend himself from magic, they can make an attack roll against the opponents caster level check.
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="merciful"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Merciful&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blade refuses to kill any living being, specifically any creature termed alive, intelligent or soulled, doing only subdual damage to these creatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When this blade deals damage treat it as normal for the purposes of &lt;strong&gt;Damage Resistance&lt;/strong&gt;. Then apply all damage as &lt;strong&gt;subdual damage&lt;/strong&gt; to the creature. The blade cannot take a creature below &lt;strong&gt;-5 HP&lt;/strong&gt;, refusing to damage said creatures. It can still steal magic from them however. Note that some creatures are soulled, but can't go below &lt;strong&gt;0 HP&lt;/strong&gt; in which case they are brought to at most &lt;strong&gt;1 HP&lt;/strong&gt;, and any further damage from Kaern's Blade causes them to be &lt;strong&gt;Disabled&lt;/strong&gt;: unable to do any mental or physical actions until &lt;strong&gt;8 hours* or they have &lt;/strong&gt;1 HP** worth of healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ability is also affected by the owner's thoughts. Thus if an animated item was seen as a "pet" by the owner, the blade would refuse to destroy it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section4&amp;quot;" id="flavour-text"&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Flavour Text&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ability manifests as the blade passing through opponents, and causing them to feel more and more exhausted, or . Thus the blade is still used to slash or stab, but passes through the opponents instead, seemingly turning into a pale blue ghostly blade. Against creatures immune to subdual damage, it works like normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="description"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kaern's Blade is a True Chaotic intelligent magic item, it does not speak, or act in any way by itself, lying dormant most of the time. The blade's refusal to kill and Magic absorbtion are a facet of its personality, as it was originally made to destroy wards and other magical defenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blade is a pale silver colour, with glowing sky blue symbols along the length.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Saevon</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag://blog.saevon.ca,2015-10-11:roleplaying/kaerns-blade/</guid><category>magic-item</category><category>D&amp;D</category></item><item><title>Necklace of Anti-Magic</title><link>//blog.saevon.ca/roleplaying/necklace-of-anti-magic/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magical Item:&lt;/strong&gt; A Necklace that allows you to Create an aura of Anti-Magic around you.
Perfect for those pesky wizards! And great against creatures which eat magic as well, (as all magic is suppressed for a short period of time)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="summary"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1d4+1 rnds of Anti-Magic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10ft radius sphere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Takes up the &lt;strong&gt;Neck&lt;/strong&gt; slot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="anti-magic"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Anti-Magic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This acts like the spell &lt;strong&gt;Antimagic Field&lt;/strong&gt; and cannot be cast unless worn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="anti-kaern"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Anti-Kaern&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This necklace was made to fight against the Kaern, which eat magic, and spread a magical disease while doing so. Thus while allied abilities are suppressed under the field, no magic eating can occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Saevon</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag://blog.saevon.ca,2015-10-11:roleplaying/necklace-of-anti-magic/</guid><category>magic-item</category><category>D&amp;D</category></item><item><title>Vampiric Blade</title><link>//blog.saevon.ca/roleplaying/vampiric-blade/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magical Item:&lt;/strong&gt; A bloodthirsty sword that always draws blood, any wielder is filled with a slight bloodlust, and is unable to sheathe it without drawing blood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="summary"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;+3 elven thinblade (1Handed, 1d8 piercing, 18-20x2 Crit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Symbols on it pulse with a faint blood red light (rad 10' bright, rad 15' shadowy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vampiric&lt;/strong&gt;: 1d4 Con Damage on hit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cursed Item&lt;/strong&gt;: You can't sheathe the blade without it drinking blood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="description"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vampiric blade is made of adamantine (dark red color with a thin silvery hue), with glowing red symbols along the length.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Saevon</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag://blog.saevon.ca,2015-10-10:roleplaying/vampiric-blade/</guid><category>magic-item</category><category>D&amp;D</category></item><item><title>Ravaging Bow</title><link>//blog.saevon.ca/roleplaying/ravaging-bow/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magical Item:&lt;/strong&gt; An incomplete bow that multiplies every arrow it shoots. In its current broken state, it shoots 2 arrows aimed properly, and one that aims towards the user.
Don't underestimate its power! Though it targets the user as well, the bow can behead its opponents with ease, and enchants its arrows with any spell cast on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="summary"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;+3 Composite Longbow (1d8 Piercing, 125ft range, Vorpal)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;+4 Maximum Str bonus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spell Storing 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arrow Storm&lt;/strong&gt;: Shoots 3 arrows, cloning the arrow type you use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Broken Item&lt;/strong&gt;: Shoots an arrow at yourself, and 2 at the enemy (roll 2d20)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="arrow-storm"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Arrow Storm&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This bow fires three arrows, any spell that the bow has stored is applied to the arrow, and the +3 enchantment bonus (if better than the arrow) is as well. But see the &lt;strong&gt;Broken Item&lt;/strong&gt; section below. Though the bow can be given to players as a complete, unbroken version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="alert alert-warning "&gt;&lt;i class="fa fa-warning"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Optional&lt;/strong&gt;: The bow can technically be used to fire at someone with arrow catching, which wouldn't waste the arrow. If this happens, the DM can allow more spells to be added to the arrow each time its fired. Though this obviously can lead to abuse. As long as your players use it for crazy hijinks, this can be a great addition
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section4&amp;quot;" id="flavour-text"&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Flavour Text&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ability spawns the two additional arrows beside the original as it leaves the bow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="broken-item"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Broken Item&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ravaging Bow is made to seek out enemies, attempting to behead them if possible. However when it clones one of the arrows in the wrong position (aimed towards the user). Thus when attacking roll 2d20, one for the arrow flying towards you, and one for the arrows flying towards the enemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="alert alert-success "&gt;&lt;i class="fa fa-check-circle"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
You can have someone standing by with gloves of arrow catching to prevent any problems with arrows flying towards you. Remember to let the players figure out these things themselves.
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="legend"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Legend&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though the story is but a small excerpt from a much larger tale, the highlights shall be retold here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="alert alert-info "&gt;&lt;i class="fa fa-info-circle"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
All of &lt;strong&gt;Craka&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Valkyrie&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Sai&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Galthor&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Aegis&lt;/strong&gt; were Player Characters in this schene
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Craka&lt;/strong&gt;: a barbarian wielding an artifact of power (&lt;em&gt;Silvia&lt;/em&gt;), &lt;strong&gt;Valkyrie&lt;/strong&gt;: an arcane archer wielding the &lt;strong&gt;Ravaging Bow&lt;/strong&gt; and the rest of the party enter a dragon's layer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fighting the dragon (&lt;strong&gt;Sai&lt;/strong&gt;) high above a perilous drop, on a huge overhang, with a glorious battle and wounds all around, the party was pushed back, and with &lt;strong&gt;Valkyrie&lt;/strong&gt; near death, &lt;strong&gt;Sai&lt;/strong&gt; throws her off the overhang! With &lt;strong&gt;Sai&lt;/strong&gt; following after her, under the overhang to avoid damage from the members above. &lt;strong&gt;Craka&lt;/strong&gt;, thinking fast jumps down after them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Activiting Backlash Drain (syncing all damage and healing between him and &lt;strong&gt;Sai&lt;/strong&gt;, and doing extra damage to both of them). &lt;strong&gt;Valkyrie&lt;/strong&gt; takes one last shot, hoping to defeat &lt;strong&gt;Sai&lt;/strong&gt; before he finishes her off, and rolls&amp;hellip; 2 natural 20's! (after confirming the crit) With &lt;strong&gt;Craka&lt;/strong&gt;'s and &lt;strong&gt;Sai&lt;/strong&gt;'s health being synced together, a triple beheading occurs as the three of them crash into the ground below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="alert alert-success "&gt;&lt;i class="fa fa-check-circle"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
While the rest of the party was not mentioned, that in no way implies their lack of awesomeness, just that they weren't really part of the beheaded trio (In this case &lt;strong&gt;Galthor&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Aegis&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Thrisperios&lt;/strong&gt; (An NPC which the &lt;strong&gt;Craka&lt;/strong&gt;'s Player took over)
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="alert alert-info "&gt;&lt;i class="fa fa-info-circle"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
The rest of the tale will be posted sometime under "Zai'Ren: The Chronicles of &lt;em&gt;Silvia&lt;/em&gt;"
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Saevon</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag://blog.saevon.ca,2015-10-09:roleplaying/ravaging-bow/</guid><category>magic-item</category><category>D&amp;D</category></item><item><title>Mystic Eye Collection Goggles</title><link>//blog.saevon.ca/roleplaying/mystic-eye-collection-goggles/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magical Item:&lt;/strong&gt; A cursed pair of eye goggles that is used to steal the eyes of creatures. It doubles as a torture device due to its method of extracting them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="summary"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attacks creatures within &lt;strong&gt;30 feet&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1/rnd&lt;/strong&gt; do a &lt;strong&gt;Ref 20&lt;/strong&gt; or be forced to wear them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concentration 16&lt;/strong&gt; or launch an eye every &lt;strong&gt;10rnds&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When shapeshifting with eyes, you get its abilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Takes up the &lt;strong&gt;Headband&lt;/strong&gt; slot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cursed Item&lt;/strong&gt;: Can't be taken off&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="extraction"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Extraction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any creature wearing these goggles will see red marks appearing over everything they focus on. The more they focus on something the brighter the mark on it. The less they focus, the darker (or non-existent) the mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a creature focuses on something for too long they feel some pressure build up behind their eyes, until, the eye is popped out of its socket, and launched towards the targeted mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When an eye is launched, a hard protective case is build up around it in the shape of a cylindrical glass container, a &lt;em&gt;Stasis Glass&lt;/em&gt;. The eye is held in a stasis field which prevents any damage unless the container itself is opened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="how-its-used"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;How it's Used&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Goggles are attracted to any creature with eyes that is within 1 size category of its size. When within &lt;strong&gt;30 feet&lt;/strong&gt; of such a creature they fly at their eyes, attaching themselves. The target gets a &lt;strong&gt;Reflex Save (DC: 20)&lt;/strong&gt; to block, though the goggles will keep trying &lt;strong&gt;1/rnd&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Every 10rnds&lt;/strong&gt; hereafter the target will need to do a &lt;strong&gt;concentration check (DC: 16)&lt;/strong&gt; to not focus too much (and launch 1 eye).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Goggles are considered a &lt;strong&gt;Headband&lt;/strong&gt; magical item, thus preventing you from using any goggles, eye glasses or other such items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Goggles are considered a cursed item for the sake of getting them off, thus &lt;strong&gt;Remove Curse&lt;/strong&gt; will make them fall off, after which they will take &lt;strong&gt;1d10&lt;/strong&gt; rnds to recover (launching one of their eyes on failure).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Goggles are usually encountered as a stranded item, acting like a trap. However in reality these Goggles are used to collect Mystic Eyes, thus there is a way to control them. The Goggles are created with a small container to hold them. The container has an arcane symbol to press when you need to stop the goggles from attacking things, and another to get them to start up again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="stasis-glass"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Stasis Glass&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any eye in a Stasis Glass can't get any damage until the container breaks. This makes it the best way to store eyes until you have a need for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to a quirk in its production any shapeshifting while holding an eye grants the user that eye. This takes up the &lt;strong&gt;Headband&lt;/strong&gt; slot, preventing any other magic items from functioning. You can have as many eye changes as is available to your current form, thought this is mandatory. Using this you can change eye colour, shape and other such details. If you hold more eyes than your form has, you get to choose which ones work (or roll for randomness).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardness:&lt;/strong&gt; 15&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HP:&lt;/strong&gt; 20&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aura:&lt;/strong&gt; Strong Transmutation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the Stasis glass is broken, it disappears, but the contents fall out (and are probably ruined)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Saevon</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag://blog.saevon.ca,2013-11-20:roleplaying/mystic-eye-collection-goggles/</guid><category>magic-item</category><category>D&amp;D</category></item></channel></rss>