<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Saevon.ca</title><link>//blog.saevon.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link href="/feeds/game.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><item><title>Review: Prison Architect</title><link>//blog.saevon.ca/review/review-prison-architect/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Prison Architect is a game about creating and managing a prison. You get a plot of land, and slowly build up a secure facility, getting money from the government for storing prisoners, and from grants (quests).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section2&amp;quot;" id="review"&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="alert alert-warning "&gt;&lt;i class="fa fa-warning"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
This game is in Alpha, thus many of the features I recommend and complain about could be planned for.
This game was pretty fun, don't drop it just cause of this review
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prison Architect was a pretty fun game to play, though I had some trouble at first, I slowly figured out how to make money and actually expand my prison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game itself involves mostly planning out your building and the rooms inside of it. So it lives up to its name as you really are an architect. There is of course more, such as planning out a regime for the prisoners, hiring staff, and setting up patrols, but the main focus is on design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section2&amp;quot;" id="gameplay"&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Gameplay&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="staff"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Staff&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Controlling your staff is still very raw, they just walk around doing whatever tasks they should do with no input from you. The only staff member you can really control is the Guard. A guard can be told to patrol, or to hang out around a specific room, or just to go somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main problem I saw with the staff, was that it was very hard to make multiple Cell Blocks. I tried to make a seperate High Security facility, but all of a sudden all my staff wanted to use its Staff Room to take breaks, "Oh look it has better wi-fi??". This also meant that some of my cooks decided to take over the Kitchen and my other one was understaffed, and other such problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="tutorial-descriptions"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Tutorial &amp;amp; Descriptions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tutorial was pretty small, and had you start with an already running prison, this meant that I missed out on a lot of the requirements for how to actually build my prison, and instead learned the controls. Instead &lt;em&gt;Tips&lt;/em&gt; might have been more useful while I was building my prison from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While playing the actual game I found most of the object to be completely useless, as I had no idea what they do. I still have no Idea whether people used the TVs I installed, or if they did nothing. The game needs a more sims like interface, you can already see the different criteria for a prisoner's happiness, the in game objects just need a "Recreation++, Energy&amp;ndash;" that tells you the result of a prisoner using the object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some rooms actually have requirements for their use, such as a workshop needing 2 types of tables (a Saw and Press), and you can't tell how much of each you'll need in the room. A Kitchen has 3 things it needs, and I still am not sure how to make my cooks support more people. Thus the game needs an expanded information window for objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarily I filled up some rooms with useless looking items, why is a filing cabinet needed for an office? what happens if I install more? There should be some benefit, more importantly do prisoners use the chairs, sofas and tables that normally go for staff?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at utilities it was sometimes hard to work with overlapping water and electricity cables/pipes. Deleting just one was especially hard during such times. Also it wasn't obvious how much electricity/water an object would use, and big vs small pipes should also have a number indicating the maximum they can carry. Electricity also has 2 types of requirements, a &lt;em&gt;small&lt;/em&gt; cable, aka if its close enough to the electricity it automatically gets connected, and a &lt;em&gt;big&lt;/em&gt; cable, aka it needs a cable to connect to it. It would be nice to know which things need what, though as far as I can tell only lights need &lt;em&gt;small&lt;/em&gt; ones. This actually confused me for a bit as CCTV cameras seemed to work, but I guess I just coincidentally put them next to &lt;em&gt;big&lt;/em&gt; cables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="cell-blocks"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Cell Blocks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned earlier it was hard to divide the place into cell blocks, I could limit areas to staff only, or to max security, but my staff didn't care. So while I wanted a block to have next to no staff, in case of riots I close it down and call in the Riot squad, thus losing no people, I couldn't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="prison-capacity"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Prison Capacity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the game you can either have your prison open for new prisoners, or not. It was annoying to have to open then close the prison, as I specifically made the place for 40 people. I couldn't just say my capacity is 40, then have prisoners come in, or better say the prison is for 30 Med risk, 5 Low risk and 5 High risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This meant that if my prison was running smoothly, and I needed some prisoners I would turn it on, then go start building my new wing, and forget to turn it back off! Thus I would be over capacity, I knew it was too late, a riot was about to happen as the prisoners near starved. But I could do nothing, it would have been nice to ship people back out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="rooms"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Rooms&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game allows for a very nice variaty of rooms, I felt pretty satisfied by them. While more might be nice, it had all I really needed for a prison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only real problem I saw with rooms was the minimum size requirements, 5x5 for a holding cell? why not 4*7. Maybe a 25m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; limit instead?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="riots"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Riots&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike some of the other people online, I had no problem keeping the number of riots down, and once I got a base prison working riots only happened when I screwed up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However I'm not sure why, but the prisoners just ran around breaking stuff and killing guards, not trying to escape? Perhaps this was an AI thing though as my prison was sort of confusingly layed out (all the better to trap people in).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/section&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Saevon</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag://blog.saevon.ca,2014-01-08:review/review-prison-architect/</guid><category>prison architect</category><category>game</category></item><item><title>Review: Game Dev Tycoon</title><link>//blog.saevon.ca/review/review-game-dev-tycoon/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Game Dev Tycoon is an interesting game that puts the player into the shoes of a game developer from the 80's. Re-invent your favourite games, combat piracy, or even embrace it. Its a unique game due to its differing gameplay between the legit and pirated versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section2&amp;quot;" id="review"&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick warning, this review is written just before the move to the 3rd office, and thus might not fully reflect all the game options. I just felt it was best to write this while its fresh in my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.greenheartgames.com/2013/04/29/what-happens-when-pirates-play-a-game-development-simulator-and-then-go-bankrupt-because-of-piracy/"&gt;See this link for details about the piracy aspect.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="controls"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Controls&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game uses a menu for most of its controls, you click on the screen and a menu opens up. I found this a bit unweldy, as sometimes this meant it went above the other icons at the top, making them hard to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also a minor bug that made me sometimes manipulate a menu in the background while I was on the "New Game" window. I'd be trying to click to type the game name, but be clicking on menu options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One suggestion which I thought would be nice, would be to highlight staff when you hover over them, that would make it more obvious that there are seperate menus. Thought it was pretty clear after a click or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="gameplay"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Gameplay&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the game was a bit confusing, I was always just guessing what options to choose, and sometimes the game I imagined and the game that I apparantly made didn't match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game creation menu was nice, but sometimes I wish I could cross some genres such as Zombie/Horror.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three stages were also a little confusing, I had already made tons of games by this point, yet the requirements still eluded me. If I was actually making games, after that many games and game reports I would have long since compiled the effects of each stage on the topics and genres. While I sometime get hints saying "+++?" it just didn't seem like I was getting enough for my efforts, sure I could have actually written reports myself, but this is a casual game to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also found the "Design" and "Technology" bubbles to be confusing, I had no idea what it meant to get better points there, except that it was probably good. Nor how each staff member and choice could effect it. My characters had stats, but I couldn't figure out why I'd care for that very reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research was pretty well done, I found that I could mostly guess when I'd get lots of research points, it was intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When choosing projects to work on, I felt I should have more control over who does what. While I could train, and research individually, it would be nice to do that as a group as well, especially if the rest of my team has nothing to do. Conversely I felt that my staff could produce multiple games, as I could do them by myself at the start, especially when I really needed money, and didn't mind going red to get money faster&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a similar topic, the medium game didn't tell me my team would have been swamped and incapable of finishing it without giving 130% each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="graphics"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Graphics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the graphics to be to my liking, the cartoonish sprites, and backgrounds to be very fitting. They didn't take too much of the focus, making you see the whole office as important, rather than focusing on your individual avatar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the avatar, I found there wasn't too much options for making an avatar, I think hair style and colour could have been seperated. Otherwise I had all the options I needed to get someone I liked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time bar at the top left was not very well done either, as I found the numbers just faded away and were unimportant to me. If it was more obvious what year it was (1980 + the given year I guess) it might have been nice, especially when I was talking to my friends about how I released these cool games in (what year would this be again?). I remember one conversation vividly, where my friend stated, "maybe the world isn't ready for your ground breaking Zombie/Sim :P", and I took forever to figure out what year that was in real time. The other time values could have been better shown as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section3&amp;quot;" id="sounds"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Sounds&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the sounds were okay, they were reminiscent of the much older games I liked to play, and totally fit in with the time and feel of the game. However there wasn't much more about them, thus I can see how the developers took their own gameplay to heart, not putting much effort into the sounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I did like them, and feel that the game really didn't need much effort in this category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section2&amp;quot;" id="conclusion"&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game was a very fun game, however I still felt there was room for improvement. I wish the best of luck to the developers of this game, and hope their sequel or expansion is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;section class="&amp;quot;section section2&amp;quot;" id="reference"&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.greenheartgames.com/2013/04/29/what-happens-when-pirates-play-a-game-development-simulator-and-then-go-bankrupt-because-of-piracy/"&gt;Piracy in a game dev game!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Saevon</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag://blog.saevon.ca,2013-10-04:review/review-game-dev-tycoon/</guid><category>game dev tycoon</category><category>game</category><category>Greenheart Games</category></item></channel></rss>